// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is music?",
    answer: "Sounds which have a variety of frequencies and are pleasant to hear",
    options: [
      "Sounds which have a variety of frequencies and are pleasant to hear",
      "It's culture",
      "combinations of sounds",
      "It's an art that people use to enjoy"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Whis is not a catagory of music?",
    answer: "Dance",
    options: [
      "Pop",
      "Indian",
      "Dance",
      "Regge"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "How many notation are there in Western music?",
    answer: "13",
    options: [
      "1",
      "5",
      "12",
      "13"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Who composed'The eroica symphony'?",
    answer: "Ludwin van Beethoven",
    options: [
      "Ludwin van Beethoven",
      "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
      "Johann Sebastian Beach",
      "Joseph Haydn"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What does this symbol '#' indicate in western music?",
    answer: "Sharp",
    options: [
      "Treble clef",
      "Bass clef",
      "Half note",
      "Sharp"
    ]
  },
    
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: " .......... is a large instrumental encemble typical of classical  music, which combines instruments from different families?(fill in the blanks)?",
    answer: "Orchestra",
    options: [
      "Orchestra",
      "Rag",
      "Drama",
      "Band"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which one of the following notations is not included in indian music?",
    answer: "We",
    options: [
      "Sa",
      "Re",
      "We",
      "Ga"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Who is the composer of the Sri Lankan national anthem?",
    answer: "Ananda Smarakoon",
    options: [
      "Sunil Shantha",
      "Ananda Smarakoon",
      "Rabindranath Tagore",
      "W.D. Amaradeva"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "One of the below-mentioned instruments is not a traditional instrument of Sri Lanka?(Find it)?",
    answer: "Harap",
    options: [
      "Harap",
      "Hakgediya",
      "Dawla",
      "Flute"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the musical mode in the  indian classical music tradition used in an improvised performance?",
    answer: "Raga",
    options: [
      "Jazz Music",
      "Raga",
      "Thaal",
      "Bilawal"
    ]
  },
];





